
export const quizQuestions_7 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of React Hooks useCallback and useMemo?',
      choices: [
        'To handle asynchronous operations',
        'To memoize functions and values for performance optimization',
        'To create new components',
        'To replace the use of the useEffect hook',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To memoize functions and values for performance optimization',
    },
    {
      question: 'Explain the concept of Higher Order Components (HOCs) in React.',
      choices: [
        'Components with enhanced styling capabilities',
        'Components that return other components',
        'Components used for server-side rendering',
        'Components that handle asynchronous operations',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'Components that return other components',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the React Router Switch component?',
      choices: [
        'To switch between different React applications',
        'To toggle between light and dark themes in React',
        'To conditionally render routes based on matching',
        'To replace the use of the Link component',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To conditionally render routes based on matching',
    },
    {
      question: 'How does Reacts PureComponent differ from a regular component?',
      choices: [
        'PureComponent is used for functional components only',
        'PureComponent automatically implements shouldComponentUpdate with a shallow prop and state comparison',
        'PureComponent has access to additional lifecycle methods',
        'There is no difference between PureComponent and a regular component',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'PureComponent automatically implements shouldComponentUpdate with a shallow prop and state comparison',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the React Hook useEffect?',
      choices: [
        'To handle user input in functional components',
        'To create and manage side effects in functional components',
        'To update the component state in class components',
        'To define lifecycle methods in functional components',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To create and manage side effects in functional components',
    },
    {
      question: 'Explain the concept of "render props" in React and provide an example.',
      choices: [
        'A pattern where a component\'s render method receives a function as a prop',
        'A technique to replace the use of state in functional components',
        'A method to render components in React',
        'A way to conditionally render components based on props',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'A pattern where a component\'s render method receives a function as a prop',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of the React.Fragment element?',
      choices: [
        'To create fragments of code in JSX',
        'To improve performance in React applications',
        'To replace the use of div elements in JSX',
        'To handle asynchronous code in React',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To create fragments of code in JSX',
    },
    {
      question: 'How does React handle forms, and what is the purpose of controlled components?',
      choices: [
        'React uses the DOM to handle forms, and controlled components are not needed',
        'React uses a separate library for form handling, and controlled components are used for validation',
        'React uses a virtual DOM to handle forms, and controlled components are used to manage form state',
        'React handles forms using controlled components to manage form state through React state',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'React handles forms using controlled components to manage form state through React state',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the role of the ErrorBoundary component in React, and how is it implemented?',
      choices: [
        'To catch JavaScript errors during rendering and update',
        'To display error messages in the console',
        'To handle asynchronous errors in React components',
        'To create custom error messages for components',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'To catch JavaScript errors during rendering and update',
    },
    {
      question: 'What are React hooks, and how do they enhance functional components?',
      choices: [
        'React hooks are a way to create custom components in React',
        'React hooks are functions that allow functional components to have state and lifecycle features',
        'React hooks are used to create animations in functional components',
        'React hooks are a replacement for class components',
      ],
      correctAnswer: 'React hooks are functions that allow functional components to have state and lifecycle features',
    },
  ],
}